Heiwa Fansubs Presents:
Great Detective Conan
Challenge to Kudo Shin'ichi
Shin'ichi?
Yeah.
You can see it, too, huh?
There's nothing wrong with my eyes, is there?
Yeah.
What's strange is...
Nylon string!
They're making fools of us.
In an instant,
my psychic powers will awaken...
...and, by psychokinesis,
my thoughts alone will keep it floating in air.
Geez, Dad!
Say! Who would do such a thing and why?
Dunno.
What I do know is...
That the written challenge was meant for us.
"Please enjoy yourself"
There's one other thing that's clear.
What is it you're saying I've overlooked?
That if we lose our calm in this situation
then it can be said...
...we will surely be defeated.
Even when you are comparatively calm,
you can't remember anything.
Huh?!
I know!
My great-grandmother's birthday.
You don't know.
This is that murder case that occurred...
...while being broadcast live on TV.
Ah, that one!
"Magic"
The person with supernatural powers,
Washimi Jiro-san!
The psychic, Washimi Jiro-san,
rated as one of the world's best...
...at age 7, he appeared as just a boy
on a psychic TV show.
He made a vivid debut showing off his skills.
Spoon bending with will-power,
spirit photography and ESP telekinesis ability!
ESP exists.
Tonight, let me...
...show it to you.
"New Sensation Battle Program
The Showdown"
Now, let's get started tonight.
Our New Sensation Battle Program...
- The Showdown!
I'm your Master of Ceremonies,
Harada Takayuki, and this is...
His assistant, Mizutani Asako!
- Glad you could join us!
Now, today's showdown is the psychic vs.
the great detective high school student!
Will it be the self-described "born psychic,"
Washimi Jiro showing off the existence of ESP?
Or will it be the one who boasts of
his outstanding reasoning power...
...the great detective Kudo Shin'ichi who will
see through the secret of his ESP powers?
My psychic ability contains
no secrets, tricks or gimmicks.
Because it isn't magic.
But excuse me, Washimi-san.
Truth is, I'm skeptical about ESP.
I'm sorry.
How about you, Kudo-kun?
If I had to say if I believed in
or didn't believe in ESP...
...well, I'd say I don't.
I will be correcting your conceptions.
You will tell me during this broadcast...
"I've been mistaken"...
...and then apologize to me.
What's this?!
Right here we heard the psychic Washimi Jiro-san
tell the high school student great detective...
Listen up. Unless I call "cut,"
you will never stop those cameras!
"Director - Ogasawara Isao"
- Got that?
- Roger.
Mori-san.
"Private Detective - Mori Kogoro"
Eh?
You explained the gist of today's program
to Kudo-kun, didn't you?
Don't worry, don't worry.
More importantly, Oga-chan.
Give me more of this.
This bouncing?
This.
Then, these are it. Go ahead.
Yeah.
These are truly ordinary spoons.
If you would please.
I shall bend this spoon
with my psychic abilities.
Ah, incredible!
It's bent. Let's compare it to one
of the ordinary spoons.
It's different.
"Shin'ichi's Childhood Friend
Mori Ran"
That's magnificent, isn't it?
My psychokinesis is among
the top class levels of the world.
- What's that!
- Incredible!
Anyone can do that.
With skilled hands and a little practice.
Isn't that just magic?
I bent mine with psychokinesis.
This was an authentic spoon bending.
Why won't you believe?
Washimi-san, weren't you taught when you
were little that you aren't supposed to lie?
For a long time now...
...I've thought I couldn't forgive
a person who deceives like this.
You should be ashamed!
Did you... just insult me?
Even if I did insult you, that'd be okay
since you're a fraud anyway.
I am not a fraud!
While you guys didn't have it...
...I've had this power since I was a kid!
Very well.
If you're willing to go that far...
...I'll ask you to prove it here.
Right everyone?
How about it?
Let's see you do this, right!
With your psychic abilities...
...please kill me.
Ehh!
You won't regret it?
Regret?!
Please let it be so.
I'd love to see your power.
I and everyone in the audience.
And everyone in front of their TV sets as well!
For treating me as a fool and taking
my psychic abilities to task as fraud...
...you can repent for it in the afterworld.
As you wish, I will kill you!
You other people leave.
Oi, oi, give me a break.
What kind of program is this?
- Harada-san!
Please hang in there, Harada-san!
Harada-san!
Everyone, please be quiet!
Shouldn't you stop it?
Fool.
People don't die from ESP.
But...
Don't worry.
Harada-san, are you okay?
Harada-san!
Harada-san! Are you okay?
It can't be...
This is bad!
He has...
...been killed.
He really is dead!
Are you satisfied with this?
You, who made me go this far...
...and who wouldn't believe
in ESP no matter what.
You're all fools!
Stupid!
I don't believe in ESP.
Are you insulting me as well?
This is a case of murder.
An impossible crime has happened
in front of TV cameras.
There must certainly be some trick behind it.
I will absolutely bring out the truth.
There is just one truth.
It's best not to declare
you'll reveal the truth like that.
Because he was killed by
my psychic abilities and not some trick.
There was definitely a trick.
I just have to see through to what it was.
It's not possible to see through something
that wasn't there to begin with.
If you go out in front of the cameras there
and say, "I was wrong" and apologize...
I'll forgive you.
Live Broadcast
"The Showdown"
"There's just one studio door."
"As there was no one going in or out..."
"...this can be considered a closed-room case."
"The criminal..."
"...is definitely in this studio!"
Even if you investigate it,
you won't come up with anything.
He was killed by psychic abilities.
Mine.
Washimi-san, when I said
I would elucidate the trick...
...I wasn't referring to your trick.
What?
It's not that other side of you.
The chief suspect in Harada-san's murder...
...is you.
"AD - Ota Awase"
Me?!
"Program Assistant
Mizutani Asako"
It wasn't me!
"AD - Nakamura Monjin"
Don't joke around!
"Harada's Dresser
Hayashi Seiko"
Why me?
You 5 who were on the stage then
are all suspects.
- "Harada-san!"
What do you think you're suggesting...
I thought you were
a little cleverer than that.
You ADs, Ota-san and Nakamura-san.
Harada-san was very tyrannical
towards the both of you.
"I told you I wanted
an unsweetened drink, you moron!"
"I'll kill you!"
"You drink it. There, there..."
There are a lot of jerks
like him in our world.
But that's not a reason to kill him!
His assistant, Mizutani Asako-san.
It's not ridiculous to count you
as the criminal, either.
"Shall we have some fun tonight?"
"Asako-chan?"
When you've aiming for the top,
you can endure anything.
But, if I kill someone,
that all goes poof, now doesn't it!
His dresser, Hayashi Seiko-san.
You, too, seem to have a motive.
"Excuse me... a friend of mine
is a fan of yours. Please sign this!"
"Ala, I don't have a pen."
"I thought I had one in my purse..."
"Pen?"
"Ugly! Just get away from me!"
"I'm sorry!"
If I didn't like it,
I'd just have quit and been done with it.
It'd be foolish to kill him.
And...
Washimi-san...
I withdraw my previous statement.
Washimi-san isn't a suspect.
Yeah. Because I'm not a suspect.
I'm the criminal.
No. You're not even a suspect.
Because Harada-san didn't die from ESP.
What are you saying!
The one who killed him was me.
My psychic abilities.
Take back what you said.
I understand completely who
the true criminal is and what their trick was.
No matter how many times you say it...
It wasn't ESP.
And you said you believed in ESP...
What's that!?
What I couldn't believe in then
was you, Shin'ichi!
This is bad...
It bent!
- Seriously? You bent it?
- It bent, it bent!
Subtly... It bent subtly.
Hey!
Will you withdraw...
...those words you said just now...
...if I use my psychic ability
to kill your girlfriend?
Go ahead, go ahead!
I was going to ask you
to do it once more anyway.
You'll be regretting those words
for the rest of your life.
Hey!
Don't worry.
Trust me.
Ran!
That boy detective just went and did this!
Hey! Leggo!
You mustn't, Mori-san!
Mori-san!
Stop!
Ran!
Sir. What are you doing here?
Jerk!
What have you done to my daughter?
Sir, wait. Calm down.
Are you okay?
Ran! Ran...
You, do something!
Heart massage or artificial respiration
or hit her with your hand, right!
No, you're wrong, I said.
Enough already! I'll do it.
You pervert!
Ran!
What on earth is this?
I'm sorry.
I asked her to play dead.
What was that?!
I'm sorry.
A person can't be killed by ESP.
On what basis have you been
declaring that up till now?
You saw me strangle Harada there, didn't you?
My basis is the cause of death
that has appeared on Harada-san's body.
Cause of death?
Yes.
If Harada-san was strangled...
...he should be showing signs of
cyanosis and extravasation of blood.
However, neither can be seen on Harada-san.
Confirmation of that was
the sweat on his forehead.
And then...
Just as he was on the verge of death,
Harada-san's body jumped and he clutched his heart.
That was a symptom of poisoning
by an intravenous injection.
There are several types of poison
that could do that.
Considering how quick his death was...
...the criminal used a poison
that would cause a cardiac arrest.
For example, potassium chloride.
Moreover, it was injected into
his jugular vein to be close to his heart.
Harada-san's death was caused by
acute heart failure and shock.
By the way...
...potassium chloride is used for
death penalty executions in America...
...and its immediate effectiveness
is pre-eminent.
Harada was killed with poison?
I don't use poisons.
Thing is, I never even got close to Harada.
What are you saying?
That's right.
And that's why the suspects are
these four other than Washimi-san.
Just a moment!
When Harada-san started his suffering...
...there was no one touching him.
Well, there wasn't even anyone at his side.
In a situation like that...
...who can you say killed him with poison?
That's right.
That's how it was.
I guess it was my psychic powers
that killed Harada-san!
Washimi-san, please listen to me carefully.
That suffering Harada-san
was going through at the start...
...was just a performance.
A performance?
Yes.
The purpose of this program was to pull
a Dokkiri on Washimi-san.
(hidden camera surprise prank)
Isn't that right, Sir?
Sir, you knew all about that, didn't you?
Eh... Well, um...
Is that right, Dad?
You made Shin'ichi appear
because you knew about that?
Well... I didn't know all the details...
They just mentioned,
how do I put it, a Dokkiri and...
I'm sorry.
Those of you with the program's staff...
...didn't believe in Washami-san's
psychic abilities from the start.
And so, in order to make Washami-san
a laughingstock on a live broadcast...
...you prepared a Dokkiri for him.
But what about the scarf?
Didn't it look like someone was
actually strangling him with it?
Yes.
This scarf was evidence of the Dokkiri.
This scarf was prepared with
a shape-memory alloy.
Shape-memory alloys...
...remember the shape
they were given at high temperatures.
Even if power is added to them
and they are deformed...
...it's possible by applying a constant temperature,
for them to return to their original shape.
It's used for the wires in Ran's bra.
That way, even if they are
deformed during washing...
...once the bra is put back on, your own body
temperature will return it to its form-fitting shape.
Excellent, aren't they?
Idiot!
How would Shin'ichi know that?
What? What?
Ran, you wear such a thing?
Ah! Don't tell me you guys...
...are in that sort of relationship!
I'm sorry.
Well, anyhow...
...Harada-san took advantage of that property.
While pretending to be suffering...
...he heated the scarf with his hands,
making the ends stand up.
That made it look as though Washami-san
was strangling him with his psychic abilities.
Then...
What about that bruise?
This too, was evidence of the Dokkiri.
Oh.
The bruise disappeared.
The bruise was simply makeup.
Ala? Then...
He's really dead.
I see.
In other words, the criminal is...
You! Makeup man!
You're the criminal who,
under Harada-san's approval...
...prepped this makeup, aren't you?
Eh, Makeup man?
Such a thing!
How terrible!
I only told him how to use that makeup.
Oi, Sir.
Ah... it was Harada-san who had the Makeup man
teach him about creating the bruise...
...who made it look as if he was dying and who,
when the timing was right...
...was going to call Washimi-san a fool.
Harada-san's the one who hatched this plan.
Hmm... it was like that.
But, how did this bruise
end up on her neck?
In her case, there wasn't a chance for her
to put on this makeup, was there?
That's right.
I guess it was you, Makeup man!
Like I said...!
There was still some makeup
stuck to Harada-san's scarf...
...so I asked her to
deliberately rub it into her neck.
"Trust me."
"Rub the scarf into your neck and act out
the same behavior Harada-san did."
In other words...
...while Harada-san, as part of the
composition of this Dokkiri program...
...was running around,
acting like he was suffering...
...someone among these 4 people
truly poisoned him.
That's how it was.
You're wrong.
The criminal who killed Harada-san.
That was...
You're wrong!
It was me!
It was my psychic abilities!
Watch closely.
Are you okay?
Because I wasn't calm,
my aim slipped a little is all.
Thing is...
...who was it among us you were
going to say gave him that poison?
Washimi-san.
Please show me the pen in your pocket.
The criminal used a pen-shaped syringe.
This syringe is for my
chronic diabetes condition.
A person wouldn't die of this.
For pete's sake.
The name "great detective" is crying, you.
The one I was talking about...
... is in that pocket.
Why are there two of them?
Now's your last chance
to surrender yourself to the police.
I see. Then it can't be helped.
The true criminal who killed Harada-san...
...is you!
Hayashi Seiko-san!
The one who injected the poison by playing along
with Harada-san's performance was you.
I wasn't the only one at Harada-san's side.
What's your basis for saying such a thing!
Before going on air,
you were yelled at by Harada-san.
"Ala, I don't have a pen."
"I should have one in my purse..."
"A pen?"
"Ugly! Just get away from me!"
"I'm sorry."
At that time, you did have a pen.
Even though Ran could have loaned you one...
...you ran off to borrow a pen from someone.
Why was that?
I just completely forgot I had one.
You say you completely forgot about it,
but now you have no pens.
Why is that?
That's...
...because after injecting
the poison into Harada-san...
...you snuck that pen
into Washimi-san's pocket.
"Sir, wait. Calm down!"
"Are you okay?"
You were intending to place
the blame on Washimi-san.
However, you were afraid
of getting caught by me...
...so you tried to kill
both Washimi-san and I.
Though you continue to play the innocent...
Well, when the investigation
checks the syringe...
...they'll find a minute amount of
your sebum DNA from it, won't they?
For example, even if you had
wiped away your fingerprints.
That's right.
It was me.
Why?
Why would you kill Harada-san?
Why, you ask?
I believed Harada's words when
he told me I'd make my debut someday...
...so I committed myself to Harada for 7 years.
My body, heart and time
all went to Harada's use.
And then, finally, I was supposed to
become his assistant on this show.
His assistant?
That's right.
Your position was going to be mine.
Yet even so,
Harada went and transferred you in.
I couldn't forgive that!
That's why I killed him.
- "Harada-san!"
It was Harada's just desserts.
This program was all screwed up,
so it was a nice touch.
If I can't make my debut...
...then I've had enough already!
Let me go!
No one understands my feelings after all!
I don't want to understand
a criminal's feelings.
But...
...there is one thing I do understand.
For those guys who
exert themselves respectably...
...God is certainly preparing
a reward for them.
We don't know when that will come.
No one knows that!
But, that's life's Dokkiri.
It would have been better if
you had waited just a little longer, too.
Yes, well then, thanks for your hard work.
Withdraw, please.
No...
Wait!
You're wrong! It's not her!
I'm a witness!
The murderer is this psychic, Washimi Jiro!
My psychic abilities have been restored!
It's true...
It's true, I've had these strange powers
ever since I was a child!
They don't believe.
If you don't believe,
then I'll kill all of you!
"Magic"
Nothing's opening!
Eh? That's wrong?
Fool. The real one is...
"Dokkiri"
We did it! It opened!
Let's go.
Again?
Ran! Are you okay?
Boy detective,
where did that sound come from?
Because of the echo, I don't know.
Sir, this time you remember, don't you?
I will never forget the case that day;
never forget it.
If I recall, that case was...
"After this"
Shin'ichi's New Challenge!"
"Murder by Finger Gun!"
"The Suspect is Kisaki Eri"
"This Drama is Fictional"